Afroz is committed to develop valuable relationships to drive new business ideas and growth in high-impact projects.

With experience from creative problemsolving in the technology industry, Afroz is a capable project manager with successful experience in planning, taking decisions and is highly motivated to exceed your expectations. Extensive knowledge in manufacturing processes and the development of manufacturing and logistical processes. Motivational abilities to lead a team and exceeding project requirements with clear communication skills.

Loaded with positive energy!



EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

2019 Certification in machine safety by Schmersal

2014-2019 Master of Science & Engineering, Production & Logistics, Mälardalens University 2010-2013 International social-nature studies, Danderyds Gymnasium

2007-2010 International English school in Täby

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postnord AB, Lean Project Manager



2023dec-ongoing

Responsible for implementing lean and standardized processes in all logistical centers in the Nordic countries, to win the parcel strategy.

Quandify AB, Supply-, & Production Manager 2023-2023nov



Responsible for supervising and solving technical problems for external manufacturing sites abroad, ensuring both product and supplier quality is achieved. Reviewing current partners for CE certification and making sure production and material cost are optimized through agreement with suppliers. Setting up new production lines together with testing equipment, training manufacturing sites with instructions, manuals and quality assurance.

Mycronic AB, Production & Industrialization Engineer 2021-2023

MYCRONIC

Solid background in manufacturing and supply chain processes that allows me to easily identify problems and implement solutions. Working daily with investigation and analyzing problems and devise solutions that save money, time and materials, in a clean room environment.

Maximizing productivity by ensuring minimal interruptions of work through high quality. Providing technical support to help manufacturing reach goals of lead times and costs KPI's. Review the supply chain processes through logistical and material flow, coordinating with production planning and reporting to operations director. Responsible for industrialize new products into production line and customer quality from field, as well as spare parts coordination.

chief

Chief Consulting AB,

Consultant employee as Project Manager 2020-2021

Consult Mission: Project Buyer at Mycronic

The SLX laser mask project at Myronic is a highly-large project designed to meet the trend of a new semiconductor laser mask writer. This role was responsible project buyer in this project, responsible to make sure that the suppliers and materials reach the goals of machines operating fast, reliable and at a lower cost while reaching goals on quality and safety. Responsible to drive the supplier project activities and performance to handle the escalation management from production. While focusing on developing and managing the sourcing plan through creative problem solving, finding competitive strategies on the marketplace in roadmaps and benchmarking. Coordinating both serial production and prototype suppliers through close relationship with the project team and RnD. Assisting with supplier contracts and supplier performance, agreements to maintain a strong strategy. Gained ability to secure strong relationship with suppliers and coordinating projects team goals to evaluate the project with lead times requirements and strategic procurement.

PREVIOUS POSITIONS

Production and Supply chain Manager, Industralization, Production Engineer, Project Buyer, Logistics Coordinator, Junior Project Leader, Transportation Planner & Material planner

KEY COMPETENCES

Lean, Project management, Logistics, Optimization, Problem Solving, Planning, Documentation, FIFO, Lean, Six Sigma, Continuous Improvement, Supply Chain Management, Risk assessment

SKILLS/METHODOLOGIES/CERTIFICATES

Github, Fortknox, Simulation, ExtendSim 9.0, Business System SAP &M3, SolidWorks, MS Office, Excel, PLM, ERP, Jira, Prince2

LANGUAGES

Farsi (Mother tongue) Swedish (fluently) English (fluently and certification in IGCSE and CAE)

OTHER

Driving License

HOBBIES

Hiking Travel Swimming Weight lifting

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chief Consulting AB, Consultant employee as Project Manager 2019-2020

Consult Mission: Logistics coordinator at Mycronic

This role was responsible for planning and optimizing inbound logistics flow to secure material supply. While managing and securing inventory levels, keeping the company efficiently flexible to customer needs. The role was mainly focused on coordinating the material flow to one of the production lines in a Pattern Generation factory. Had a strong ability to collaborate with different types of people, working cross functionally while having a strong process mindset. Also had a strong ability to work with continuous improvements through creative problem solving, in order to reduce unnecessary work flows in the supply chain.

Determined to give the best possible support to internal customers while being humble, but confident with a high sense of urgency understanding tasks to prioritize.

Being able to form a coordinating role where tasks were unclear from the beginning, to setting up a clear role with standardized processes and tasks in order to reach the customers goals. This was done by working confidently and having a strong ability to coordinate various departments and understanding what to prioritize in order to meet production requirements.



Scania CV AB, Junior project leader 2019

Worked as responsible project manager for a production-oriented project with a budget of approximately 5 MSEK. With the purpose of increasing the safety of automatic cells in the engine machining department, through various technical solutions. Being a very "hands-on" project with close contact with different kinds of departments. The project included risk assessments with the support from safety engineers, local maintenance, group managers and operators. Also, responsible for coordinating electrical installations with production planning, through constant follow-up with supplier and subcontractor.

Where suppliers delivered reprogramming of control systems as well as updated electrical constructions, including archiving technical documentation to both maintenance and production department. These technical solutions were followed-up through various inspections, acceptance tests and implemented working methods.

Also responsible for the financial follow-up of the project by presenting and documenting progress-reports of costs against the steering group.

This led to close contact with finance and purchasing. In addition to the project, responsible to participate and support in simulation problems from various departments.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+46705527289

EMAIL:

Afroz.shara@amail.com

WEBSITE:

(79) Afroz Mirzaie Shra | LinkedIn

https://www.scania.com/group/en/home/newsroom/news/2019/simulation-anew-tool-to-optimise-production.html

FULLTEXT01.pdf (diva-portal.org)

Afroz Mirzaie Shras, civilingenjörsprogrammet inom produktion, innovation och logistik – Mälardalens universitet (mdu.se)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Scania CV AB, Master Thesis



2018-2019

Completed graduate work in Master of Science and Engineering within simulation of production systems. The purpose was to investigate whether simulation as a tool can identify actual bottlenecks on an engine production line. The need was to map the current state of processes and identify parts within production, in order to increase the output. The simulation model showed that the production worked mainly with acute deviations that provided a picture of incorrect bottlenecks, where the model presented a clear overview of the entire production and KPI's. The results lead to change of cycle times in machines recommended from the study.

The thesis was well received and presented to the management team within engine machining, also advertised on Scania's website and LinkedIn-page. My experience in data management and computer systems led to supporting a prestudy of upgrading an internal ERP system in deviations for a much more efficient and standardized platform.

The master thesis contributed to suggesting how the company could improve their production line by utilizing simulation as a production tool, being highly marketed at the company's social media.

https://www.scania.com/group/en/home/newsroom/news/2019/simulation-a-new-tool-to-optimise-production.html



Mälardalens University, Research Assistant 2018-2019

Employed by the university to work as a research assistant in a simulation course. This involved assisting in designing the course, giving lectures and supporting in workshops and case studies. The course was a new initiative where both employees from companies such as Scania, Astra Zeneca et cetera participated together with students.

Contributed my knowledge and skills in simulation to the university while assisting lead researcher Erik Flores in Malardalens University in workshops focusing on production optimization. Assisting in solving real-life production issues from companies in the industry.

Gained experience in setting up workshops between the university and companies. This was also letting me gain growth and training in public speaking, in combination of gaining knowledge and skills in simulation as a production-optimization tool.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VOLVO

Volvo Construction Equipment, Shipment Agent Volvo Construction Equipment 2017

Was responsible for shipping and planning outbound transport from warehouse to customers, dealing with complete products such as axles and transmissions. This was done through close contact with transport planning department and transport companies. Where all technical documentation was registered in the business system, SAP. Along with a side project being responsible for updating and digitalizing working methods for packing completed axles and transmissions, in internal data systems. With the aim of forming standardized working methods with standardized worksheets, in order to improve efficiency.

Contributing with solutions to optimize material handling instructions for staff in factory. Receiving knowledge and experience in how standardization and lean-practices can improve industries and reduce waste in internal processes.

VOLVO

Volvo Construction Equipment, Bachelor Thesis Volvo Construction Equipment 2017

Completed thesis during the third year at university, focused on logistics and optimization. With the aim of optimizing inventory in the finished goods warehouse while ensuring correct FIFO prioritization.

The result was a new working method of stocking larger products by saving storage areas, optimizing FIFO and more efficient use of transportation distance. Done by analyzing truck drivers working methods and the degree of utilization of surface in the warehouse. A number of proposals was presented where suppliers of storage systems presented various offers on technical solutions. Through creative problem solving and communication with suppliers, being able to present a solution arguable with facts, improving storage-issues at a large company as Volvo.

VOLVO

Volvo Construction Equipment, *Consignee* Volvo Construction Equipment 2016

Analyzing the flow of incoming raw material, assembled parts and stock from incoming goods to entering the factory. Determined the administration of shipment documentations and invoices. Overseeing the quality of loading and unloading goods, making sure transportations companies exceeded Volvo's demands. Where arriving material was handled in the business system SAP.

Gave an insight into working with cases and problem solving along with people in neighboring work areas.

Receiving experience in communication and coordinating with various departments, with increasing knowledge in material flow and quality.